Thinking back to the first time I landed
at Laslui in the Upper Skeena, like,
it gives me goosebumps.
Just like it was very emotional.
It was wild.
Like, I'd never, like, I'd explored BC
or I thought I had,
you know, tree
planting workin’ and whatever.
But what I didn't
realize is I'd never seen
a place that didn't have cut blocks.
Like, I'd never seen a valley
without a cut block in, ever.
And we took off from
we all pile into the, Cessna Caravan,
the old one Alpine had, and we took off
and, you start heading north and,
you know, you go over the Babine
and there's still cut blocks everywhere,
and then you get into the upper
Skeena and, you know, you still have some
cut blocks go over the, the Sustut,
that there's still some cut blocks.
And then once you get past that
and up to the Duti
and you start tipping up to the
to the real headwaters
of the Skeena, there's no cut blocks.
And I remember
looking down and being like,
like I didn't
I just never knew what that looked like
before.
Just like actual untouched
wilderness.
And, yeah, it was it was very impactful.
And then,
you climb, higher and higher
and higher and, and you literally tip over
and you get up to that kind of the,
that beginning of the zone.
Called, you know, that that's called the,
the Sacred Headwaters.
And you tip over and now you're
starting to go into the well,
you can see the Arctic drainage off
to your right,
a couple valleys to your left
you can see the ice,
and then you tip on over into the Stikine
and, it's wild.
I've been now, you know, doing this
for the last seven years.
I've been on a lot of planes with a lot of
people and done that same thing.
And, you know, there's chitter
chatter and people are taking photos.
The whole way up.
But when you tip over that last little bit
and you get into the upper Stikine
everyone gets quiet
and everyone is just like,
okay, goosebumps again, that's crazy. Did.